Jay Bains

jayarjunbains@gmail.com 07775743812

London, UK

Skills:

- Programming
- Data management
- Data science and analytics
- Information technology
- Administrative support
- Technical support
- Customer service

Programming Languages:

- Python
- Java
- Java Script
- HTML
- C#
- SQL
- R

Tools:

- Git
- TensorFlow
- OpenCV
- React
- Spring Boot
- Figma
- Visual Studio
- Unity

Interests:

- Travelling
- Competitive eSports
- Pool
- Badminton
- Airsoft
- Photography
- · PC building

References:

Available upon request

Personal Summary:

With a First Class Honours degree in Computer Science from Brunel University London, I am eager for a career in software development. My academic achievements and work experience have equipped me with a solid theoretical and practical foundation necessary to contribute to the success of my future team.

Education:

BSc Computer Science, Brunel University London 08/2019 - 07/2023 Modules: Artificial Intelligence Α* **Advanced Topics Cyber Security** Α Algorithms В Digital Media and Games Full Stack Development В Α Networking Α **Usability Engineering Software Engineering**

Grade: First Class Honours.

Personal Projects:

Crime Maps

A web application built using JavaScript and Vite. The application displays an interactive heat map of crime incidents across London by leveraging the Google Maps API and fetching real-time data from the Police UK API.

Fruitify

A desktop application written in Python, utilising neural networks and machine learning for fruit and vegetable identification through computer vision techniques. The application accesses a nutritional database, providing users with detailed nutritional information in real-time.

Zero Hunger

Collaborated as part of an Agile SCRUM development team, to create an android application written in JavaScript and Java. Leveraging a full-stack approach, we developed a delivery service platform enabling restaurants to donate leftover food to those in need through coordination with local food banks.

Apple Age Inquisition

A 2D platform game using the Unity engine, aimed at enhancing my proficiency in C# programming. This project includes multiple levels and features a unique combat system, to provide players with an engaging experience.

Work Experience:

Customer Care Advisor, HeliosX, London

11/2024 - Present

- · Collaborate with Pharmacists & Clinicians to maintain high standards of clinical care and patient safety.
- Main liaison for new and existing customers, ensuring exceptional service and fostering strong relationships.
- Collect and analyse customer feedback, providing actionable insights to senior agents.

Leadership Administration Support, Xydus, London

08/2022 - 11/2022

- Collaborated with seniors to ensure adherence to compliance standards and organisational protocols.
- Management and support of IT equipment.
- Maintained and updated stakeholder records in accordance with GDPR.
- Utilised CRM software to initiate and manage new client relationships.

Sales Assistant, WHSmith, Heathrow Terminal 5

01/2020 - 10/2020

- Encouraged additional sales and delivered excellent after-sales service.
- Utilised database software to monitor and locate stock area-wide.
- Provided constant feedback on client activity and market analysis to optimise sales strategies.

Sales Assistant/Bike Mechanic, Halfords, Hayes

07/2016 - 02/2018

- Consistently achieved weekly sales targets through customer engagement and effective product promotion.
- Collaborated closely with multiple teams to ensure the completion of daily objectives.
- Efficient time management while completing multiple bike build projects to meet customer demand.